instem.com 2019-02-07

# Instem - Privacy Policy

## Instem plc Privacy Policy

### About this Privacy Policy

Instem plc and its group companies are committed to protecting your privacy.  This policy, together with the terms and conditions of use and our statement on cookies, set out the basis on which any personal data which we collect from you, through our website, will be used by us.

Please read this privacy policy carefully.  By using this website, you agree to the way in which your personal information will be used as set out in this policy.   

### Information we may collect from you and track

When you use our website, we track, collect and process personal information about you.   

This includes information which you may provide to us when you complete one of the forms on our website.  For example, you may do this to make an enquiry with us or to request further information from us about one of our products or services.  This might include a request for a quote or a virtual demonstration. 

From time to time, we also advertise vacancies on our website and you may apply for a position with us which may involve sending personal information about yourself through our website or by contacting us by email for example, if you send in a copy of your CV.  Similarly, we invite interest from students who may be looking for an internship or work experience and again, this may involve providing personal information to us. 

More generally, we may also hold information if you contact us in other ways for example, to raise an enquiry via email or perhaps over the phone. 

The information which we may hold about you will usually include your name and job title and contact details including your address, telephone number and email address.  If you are applying for a position or work experience with us, then we may also hold information about your experience and work history. We might also collect information from you about any disabilities that you may have in order for us to make reasonable adjustments if necessary for example, if you attend an interview with us.

We may also hold information about interest which you have shown in any of our products and services and may also keep a record of correspondence which you have sent to us, including a record of any complaints.

Using certain secure technologies, we are often able to track what pages on our Web site you have visited, can confirm what business entity you are associated with and identify the general location (country, state) of your business. When receiving email from us, we are also able to confirm if you have read our messages and the type of device and browser you may have been using at that time.

### How we use your information

Your personal data will be held on our records and used for the proper administration of our business, including by way of example, to deal with and process your enquiries and to provide you with any further information which you may have requested. 

From time to time we may also contact you about our products and services and which we feel may be of interest to you.  You have the right to be removed from our mailing list (known as “opting out”). You also have the right to ask to be removed from our database and that all of your information be completely erased. To do so, you can write to us at [info@instem.com](mailto:info@instem.com).  Similarly, when we send out our email marketing communications, you can click on the “Subscription Preferences & Rights” link.

Where you have sent information to us as part of an application for a vacancy or to enquire about work experience, we will use the personal information which you provide to assess your application.  We may also retain that information for future reference.

We are an international business and have offices in Europe and in other parts of the world including North America and the Far East.  This means that in some cases, the information which we collect from you may be transferred to and stored at a destination which is outside the European Economic Area.  Examples of situations in which we might transfer your details overseas to our other offices, include if you are applying for a position in one of our overseas offices or if your enquiry is best dealt with by one of those offices. 

We do take data security seriously and we will take steps as reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this policy.   Please note however that the transmission of information via the internet can never be guaranteed as entirely secure.  Therefore, whilst we will do our best to protect your personal data, we can’t guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site and therefore any transmission of data is at your own risk.

We may disclose your personal data where we are under a legal obligation to do so, for example, as explained in our Terms of Use or for our proper business purposes for example, if we were to buy or sell any business (if relevant).  We may also disclose your personal information to any member of our group of companies which means one or more of Instem plc’s subsidiaries.  From time to time we might appoint external third parties to help us with our business functions for example, external consultants and sub-contractors.  We therefore may make your data available to those entities if reasonable to do so in order to deal with your enquiry or otherwise as part of our usual business practices. 

**By providing your personal data to us, you agree to the transfer, use and storage of your data as set out in this policy.   **

If at any time you need to give information to us about another person, for example, a work colleague, then you should ensure that that person has given their consent to providing relevant details to us and you should bring this policy to their attention.  

### Cookies

We use technologies called cookies to gather information about your computer use.  A cookie is a piece of text placed on your browser or hard drive. Further information about how we use cookies can be found in our cookies statement.

### Your rights

You have the right to ensure that any information which we hold about you is accurate and up to date.  If you believe that the information that we may hold on you is incorrect or is no longer up to date, then please tell us. Our contact details are set out below.

You have the right to be removed from our mailing list (known as “opting out”); and you have the right to ask that all of your information be completely erased from our database.

You also have a right to access the personal information held about you.  To obtain a copy of the information, please write to us at the address below.  We reserve the right to request payment of a £10 charge to cover the administration cost of dealing with your access request.

**Contact Address**

Diamond Way  
Stone Business Park  
Stone  
Staffordshire  
ST15 0SD  
Email: [info@instem.com](mailto:info@instem.com)

### Other websites

Where we provide links on our website to third party sites, please note that those sites will be directly responsible for the information which you may provide to them.  If you do use other websites, the operators of those sites may collect information from you which might be used in a different way to how Instem plc and its group of companies uses information and therefore privacy policies on other websites may differ from this policy.

### Changes to our privacy policy

From time to time, we may make changes to this privacy policy in which case, a revised policy will be posted on our website.

### Contact

For the purposes of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), Instem Plc together with its subsidiary companies as appropriate, act as data controller.
